<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data → Information → Visualization on Abdullah Ahsan</title>
    <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data → Information → Visualization on Abdullah Ahsan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using LSTM to predict stock market prices for AAPL stock</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Link to Github Repo: https://github.com/abdullahahsann/AAPL-Stock-Prediction-Using-LSTM
So this was just a testing project that i did to test out LSTM. The data used is real though and is downlaoded from: https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/AAPL/history?p=AAPL.
The data is from 2017-09-20 to 2022-09-15.
First i downloaded the data as csv file from the link shared above. Then i used pandas to read the csv file.
Using matplotlib i plotted the data to see how it looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VISION AI: Real Time Video Enhancement For Surviellance</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Link to Github Repo: https://github.com/abdullahahsann/VideoEnhancementForSurviellance
Table of Contents Introduction Problem Solution Advantages of proposed system Technologies Used Hardware Results Desktop Application How to test yourself Papers that have helped me a lot Introduction Under bad weather conditions, such as fog and haze, the quality of images degrades severely due to the inﬂuence of particles in the atmosphere. Suspended particles will scatter light and result in attenuation of reﬂected light from the scene and the scattered atmospheric light will also mix with the light received by the camera and change the image contrast and color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work at Xlyexa Inc</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the next upcoming post. Where i will detail my work at Xlyexa Inc. though i&amp;rsquo;ll be limited to sharing any actual data or code. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share as much as i can.
Stay Updated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>My main work is focused on Deep Learning, Computer Vision with specific interest in GANs (General Adversarial Networks) and CNNs (Convolution Neural Networks) along with using Data Science for solving Data Lineage, Governance and Orchestration Solutions.
Currently I’m pursuing my master’s degree in data science from University of Alabama, Birmingham.
I also love participating in Kaggle Competitions, and a few in which I’ve already took part in, span from prediction of stock market volatility to SETI &amp;ldquo;alien signals&amp;rdquo; identification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gohugo-theme-ananke.pages.dev/contact/</guid>
      <description> Platform URL Email: abdullahahsan6824@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdullah-ahsann/ GitHub: https://github.com/abdullahahsann </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
